Elizabeth E. May Papers 1997.0119
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
Elizabeth E. May Papers
undated, 1901-1996
1997.0119
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
14.0 Linear feet
A noted educator, administrator, writer and researcher, Dr. May joined the faculty of the University of Connecticut in 1952 as Dean of the School of Home Economics at the University of Connecticut. She retired from the University in 1964.
May, Elizabeth Eckhardt, 1899-1996.
Biography
Elizabeth Eckhardt May, a former University of Connecticut dean, was born on 18 February 1899 in Folsom, NJ. She earned her first degree from Trenton State Normal School in Trenton, NJ. She received a Bachelor of Science, Masters of Arts, and her Doctoral Degree in Education from Columbia University. Along with these, Dr. May also received her Professional degree from the Columbia University Teachers College, specializing in Adult Education.
As a noted educator, administrator, writer and researcher, Dr. May began her career with the West Virginia University Agricultural Extension Service. She began, there, as a County Home Demonstration Agent and worked her way up through District Agent to State Specialist in Community Organization. During her tenure at West Virginia University, Dr. May became the Executive Secretary of Oglebay Institute and also was in charge of the programs run at Oglebay Park in Wheeling, WV.
Her career continued on with her appointment as Executive Secretary of the White House Conference on Children in Democracy. Following this service, she taught at both the University of Minnesota and the University of Michigan. In 1943, Dr. May was named Academic Dean and Dean of Faculty at Hood College in Frederick, MD. Dr. May joined the faculty of the University of Connecticut in 1952 as Dean of the School of Home Economics. She retired from the University in 1964.
Along with her work as Dean, Dr. May pioneered and directed a project focusing on rehabilitation of the handicapped. Her focus broadened with research in independent living for the handicapped and the elderly. In conjunction with other professors from the University of Connecticut, she conducted an International Exhibit about rehabilitation for the handicapped. Her sabbatical study entailed traveling Europe and researching European methods of rehabilitation of the handicapped. She served as a member on the President's Committee on the Employment of the Handicapped.
After her retirement from the University of Connecticut, Dr. May published two books, with her co-authors, Neva Waggoner and Eleanor Hotte, entitled Homemaking for the Handicapped (1966) and Independent Living for the Handicapped and the Elderly (1974). She continued to work in the field of rehabilitation as a consultant and a lecturer.
Elizabeth Eckhardt was married to a noted New York architect, Charles C. May. They had one child, Margaret May Kessel. Dr. May has been honored with a number of awards for her scholarly work and service. Elizabeth May died in 1996.
Scope and Content
The collection contains Dr. May's correspondence, memoranda, reports, articles, speeches, books, photographs, awards and notes pertaining to her career, although there is a small amount of personal information. The materials date from 1901 to 1994 but the bulk of the materials are concentrated in the period 1940 through 1970. Major topics included in the collection are Home Economics, Rehabilitation and related issues, and education. Of particular note and interest is her work concerning handicapped homemakers, both nationally and internationally. There is a significant amount of photographs in the collection, only a small number of which have been sorted and identified.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Dennis, Lawrence E., ed. Education and a Woman's Life. Washington, D.C.: American Council on Education, 1963. Dodd Call No. A 4185
Foott, Sydney, ed. Kitchen Sense for disabled people of all ages. London: Published for the Disabled Living Foundation by William Heinemann Medical Books, Ltd., 1976. Dodd Call No. A 4189
Gilbreth, Lillian Moller. The Quest of the One Best Way. New York: Society of Women Engineers, undated Dodd Call No. A 4188
May, Elizabeth Eckhardt, Neva R. Waggoner and Eleanor M. Boettke. Homemaking for the Handicapped. New York: Dodd, Mead and Company, 1966. Dodd Call No. C 5298
May, Elizabeth Eckhardt, Neva R. Waggoner and Eleanor Boettke Hotte. Independent Living for the Handicapped and the Elderly. Boston: Houghton Mifflin Company, 1974. Dodd Call No. C 5299
Maynard, Harold B., G. J. Stegemerten and John L. Schwab. Methods-Time Measurement. New York: McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1948. Dodd Call No. A 4190
National Manpower Council. Womanpower. A Statement by the National Manpower Council with Chapters by the Council Staff. New York: Columbia University Press, 1957. Dodd Call No. A 4187
Sherman, Helen and Marjorie Coe. The Challenge of Being a Woman: Her role in Modern Life. New York: Harper & Brothers, 1955. Dodd Call No. A 4186
Individual issues of serial publications found in the collection have been integrated into the appropriate subject area.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Margaret May Kessel in June 1997.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to the University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
University of Connecticut.; Authors; Books.; Child care; Connecticut; Correspondence; Education; Educators; Faculty; Home economics; Home economics for people with disabilities; Homemakers; Interviews; Manuscripts (document genre); Notes; Parents with disabilities; Personal papers; Photocopies; Photographs; Publications; Rehabilitation; Self-help devices for people with disabilities; Speeches; United States; Universities and colleges; Women with disabilities.
- Series I: Personal Papers, undated, 1939-1996
  - Family Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Family History (Eckhardt), undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personal Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Personal information, undated, 1973, 1979 (Box 11)
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1939-1996
    - Family
      - General, 1940-1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Family Christmas Letters, 1950-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Margaret May Letters, 1939-1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Subject
      - Correspondence A, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence B, 1991-1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence C, 1973-1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence D, 1972-1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence E, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence F, 1975-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence G, 1979-1991 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence H, 1979-1993 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence J, 1979-1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence K, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence L, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence M, 1979-1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence N, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence O, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence O, 1973-1983 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence P, 1976-1991 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Correspondence R, 1976-1991 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence S, 1986-1993 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence T, 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence W, 1979-1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence and Notes Concerning Tenants, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Subseries B: Education, undated, 1918-1996
    - Yearbook- New Jersey State Normal School, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - College English Papers, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Papers—Teacher's College, Columbia University, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - College Sociology Paper—“Leadership”, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Transcript from Teacher's College, Columbia University, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - International House, New York - Remembrances, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Dissertation
      - Rough Draft- V.1 “Experiments in Methods of Adult Learning”, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Chapter III- “An Experiment in the Music Program” Rough Draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Chapter VIII-“A Summary of the Project” Rough Draft, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Partial Bibliography (19-208), undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Volume I “Experiments in Methods of Adult Learning”, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Volume II “Experiment in Methods of Adult Learning”, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Subseries C: Subject Files, undated, 1929-1996
    - Alaska Trip, 1993 August 20 - 29 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Apartment Rental- Braddock Heights, MD, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Articles about Elizabeth E. May, undated, 1955-1962 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Articles about Elizabeth E. May (International), undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Autobiography- notes, writings, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Bibliographies (early) of E. May writings, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Braddock Heights Community Association, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Cartoon Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Community Studies/ Survey, 1929-1941 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Declaration of Covenants/ Codicil to Will, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Fulsom, NJ Church- letters and brochure, 1970-1993 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Frederick County Historical Society, 1980-1996 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Frederick County Library, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Gambrill Oak, Maywoods- notes and correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Garden Tour England, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Herbs and Wildflower Guides, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Historic Boston Booklet, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Hotel Information, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - International House- New York City, 1977-1988 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Living Will, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Maps and Directions, undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Maryland- tour guides and sites, undated (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Charles C. May- obituary and letters, 1939-1978 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Maywoods- Braddock Heights, MD, undated (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Membership Cards, 1973-1992 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Miscellaneous Writings, undated (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - National Archives, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Newspaper Articles, 1987-1994 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Obituary Material- Elizabeth E. May, undated (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Parks, Wildlife Refuges, and Mountain Parks, undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Philadelphia Maritime Museum, 1978-1986 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Philosophy- Newspaper clippings, writings and poems, undated (Box 2, Folder 71)
      - Poetry, Quotations, and Songs, undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
      - Reader's Digest- writing and miscellaneous, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Subseries D: Awards, undated, 1929-1991
    - AHEA, 1975 (Box 3)
    - Connecticut Rehabilitation Association
      - Edward P. Chester Award, 1966
      - Guest Book with photographs
    - New Jersey State Teachers College at Trenton
      - Alumni Citation, 1947
    - National Rehabilitation Association certificate, 1963 (Box 11)
    - President's Committee on Employment of the Handicapped plaque, undated
      - 25th Anniversary, undated
      - Certificate of membership, 1970-1972
      - Commendation, 1968
    - Shenandoah Apple Blossom Festival
      - Certificate of Appreciation, 1929
    - University of Connecticut
      - 100 Years of Women at UConn, 1991
      - Alumni Association Honorary Certificate, 1982
      - Recognition dinner, 1964
      - Women's Center Quilt, undated
- Series II: Employment, undated, 1918-1996
  - Ringwood, NJ - Developing wartime gardens, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Subseries A: West Virginia University, undated, 1921-1995
    - First 4-H Club Camp Picture, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - 4-H Club- Candle Lighting Ceremony and pictures, undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - “4-H Club - Leaders Manual”, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - “Pa Ain't Registered” by Leland S. Devore, Jr., undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Pamphlets- West Virginia plants and birds, undated (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - “ West Virginia Agriculture and Rural Life” by Nat T. Frame, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - West Virginia 4H “The Torch”, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - West Virginia Reunion, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Drama Festival Research
      - American Indian Costume Research, undated (Box 4, Folder 83)
      - Arabian Costume Research, undated (Box 4, Folder 84)
      - Chinese Costume Research, undated (Box 4, Folder 85)
      - Colonial Costume Research, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
      - Czechoslovakian Costume Research, undated (Box 4, Folder 87)
      - Early American Costume Research, undated (Box 4, Folder 88)
      - English, Elizabethan Costume Research, undated (Box 4, Folder 89)
      - Flags of the United States and the United Nations, undated (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Speeches and Writings of E. E. May
      - Speech Material, undated (Box 4, Folder 91)
      - “Advantages of Country Life” - outline, undated (Box 4, Folder 92)
      - “Festivals for Many Occasions” Handbook, undated (Box 4, Folder 93)
      - “How Much Canned Amusement Does Your Community Use”, undated (Box 4, Folder 94)
      - “Human Interest Stories Concerning Home Entertainment Talent”, undated (Box 4, Folder 95)
      - “Leisure and the Home”- questions for discussion, undated (Box 4, Folder 96)
      - “Leisure in the Home”- questions for discussion, undated (Box 4, Folder 97)
      - “The Other Wise Man”, undated (Box 4, Folder 98)
      - “Pigs, Pies, and Something More”, undated (Box 4, Folder 99)
      - “Pocahontas County Fair”, undated (Box 4, Folder 100)
      - “Put New Life into your County Fair”, undated (Box 4, Folder 101)
      - “The Star of Nations”- Christmas carol service, undated (Box 4, Folder 102)
      - “Reading in the Home”, undated (Box 4, Folder 103)
      - Speech as District Governor of Quota, undated (Box 4, Folder 104)
      - Speech- Untitled, undated (Box 4, Folder 105)
      - Speech- WV Quota Club- county responsibility, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 106)
      - “25 WV Fairs Feature Home Talent Entertainment”, undated (Box 4, Folder 107)
      - Published Articles at WV University, 1927-1930 (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Subseries B: Oglebay Park, WV, undated, 1927-1993
    - Oglebay Park, Wheeling, WV, undated (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - “Partnership in Learning: Resources for the Classroom” - Oglebay Institute, undated (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - “The Story of Oglebay Park”, undated (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - “Update” Oglebay Institute Newsletter and Activities Schedule, 1983, 1984, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Speeches and Writings by E.E. May
      - “An Account of the Development of the Activities Program Centering at Oglebay Park... and Development of Oglebay Institute, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 113)
      - “Home Talent Entertainment for Community Fairs” -Radio Talk, 1935 June (Box 4, Folder 114)
      - “Home Talent Entertainment: The Best Kind of Insurance for Your Fair”, undated (Box 4, Folder 115)
      - “How to Put on a Live Recreation Program”, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 116)
      - “How Waddington Farm Became Oglebay Park: A Record of Seven Seasons of Activity Programs”, 1927-1933 (Box 4, Folder 117)
      - Rough Copy - “How Waddington Farm Became Oglebay Park”, undated (Box 4, Folder 118)
      - “The Schools' Responsibility in the Education for Leisure”, undated (Box 4, Folder 119)
      - “Spiritual and Religious Value in Rural Art”, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 120)
      - “A Well Balanced Community Life” - outline for discussion, undated (Box 4, Folder 121)
      - “Who Should Be Trained for Recreational Leadership in our Colleges an Universities”, undated (Box 4, Folder 122)
      - “The Wise Use of Enforced Leisure” - outline for discussion, undated (Box 4, Folder 123)
      - Correspondence- Oglebay Institute, undated (Box 4, Folder 124)
  - Subseries C: White House Conference On Children In A Democracy, undated, 1940-1943
    - “Character Values of Play and Recreation” by Charles Kennedy, undated (Box 4, Folder 125)
    - Children in a Democracy - General Report by White House Conference, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 126)
    - Copyright Certificate for “Community Projects for Child Welfare”, undated (Box 4, Folder 127)
    - “A Guide for Wartime Planning for Children” by Marshall Field, undated (Box 4, Folder 128)
    - Notes for Speeches (Box 4, Folder 129)
    - “Report of Activities White House Conference on Children in a Democracy”, 1940-1943 (Box 4, Folder 130)
    - “The Relationship Between Problems of Children and the Problems of Manpower” by Marshall Field, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 131)
    - “Some Practical Applications of the Recommendations of the White House Conference on Children in a Democracy”, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 132)
    - Unidentified Papers (Box 4, Folder 133)
    - Speeches and Writings of E.E. May
      - Address at Annual Area “B” Child Welfare School - Conference of The American Legion, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 134)
      - “Community Projects for Child Welfare”, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 135)
      - “Dividends from a Conference”, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 136)
      - “How Can We Translate the Findings of the White House Conference into Community Action”, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 137)
      - “An Inventory of Services to Children as a Wartime Community Project for Volunteers”, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 138)
      - Memorandum on Conferences with State White House Conference Committees, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 139)
      - Untitled Speech, undated (Box 4, Folder 140)
      - “Whom to Train for Recreational Leadership”, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Subseries D: University Of Minnesota, undated, 1940-1960
    - Newsletter- “The Minnesota Plan for the Continuing Education of Women”, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 142)
    - Speeches and Writings
      - “The Art of Living”, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 143)
      - “The Community's Responsibility for Recreation”, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 144)
      - “Leisure and the Home” Soc. 146 SU, undated (Box 4, Folder 145)
      - “Leisure Time Activities in the Home” - outline for discussion, undated (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - Subseries E: Hood College, undated, 1942-1996
    - Hood Alumni, undated (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Hood College Pictures- Dean Elizabeth E. May, undated (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Hood College Centennial Celebrations and Services, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - “The Inauguration of Shirley D. Peterson” as 7th President of Hood College, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 150)
    - Joseph Henry Apple Library, undated (Box 4, Folder 151)
    - The Lawrence Marx, Jr. Resource Management Center, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Publications from Hood College, 1989-1996 (Box 4, Folder 153)
    - Speech Material, undated (Box 4, Folder 154)
    - Speeches by Other Authors (Liberal Arts), undated (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - Women and War - articles, 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Speeches and Writings
      - Chapel Talks given by E.E. May, undated (Box 4, Folder 157)
      - “College Women and National Service”, 1950-1952 (Box 4, Folder 158)
      - “The Education of Women for Effective Citizenship”, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 159)
      - “Fitting a Volunteer or Professional Career into a Life-time Plan”, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 160)
      - Fourteen Points to Serve as Guide in discussion of Problems Faced by Women..., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 161)
      - “A Freshman Inventory of Leisure-Time Skills”, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 162)
      - “Guidance in Education for Leisure”, undated (Box 4, Folder 163)
      - “Guide Posts for Leaders in Community Organization and Youth Leadership”, undated (Box 4, Folder 164)
      - “An Inventory of Myself”, undated (Box 4, Folder 165)
      - “Leadership Talk for Keystone”, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 166)
      - “Mother's Day Talk”- for men's Bible class, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 167)
      - “The 'New Dean' Gives a Progress Report”, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 168)
      - Notes for Lecture on Education of Women, undated (Box 4, Folder 169)
      - Notes on Speech to Baltimore Hood Club, undated (Box 4, Folder 170)
      - “Now in the Days of Youth”, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 171)
      - “Opportunities Open to Hood College Women”, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 172)
      - “The Responsibility of Men for Careers of Women”, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 173)
      - “Rewards and Responsibilities” Commencement address for Frederick Memorial Hospital, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 174)
      - “Rewards and Responsibilities” Speech for Nursing Commencement, undated (Box 4, Folder 175)
      - Speeches- Untitled (subject: Students), 1948 (Box 4, Folder 176)
      - “Statements for Consideration in Planning the Education of Women”, 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 177)
      - “Trends in the Education of Women”, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 178)
      - “Trends in the Hood College Curriculum”, circa 1949 (Box 4, Folder 179)
      - “What Will You Do With Your Life?”, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - Subseries F: University Of Connecticut, undated, 1945-1988
    - Home Economics
      - Annual Report- School of Home Economics, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 181)
      - Home Economics Pamphlets, undated (Box 4, Folder 182)
      - News From the School of Home Economics, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 183)
      - Correspondence- contacts from and about UCONN, 1959-1989 (Box 4, Folder 184)
      - Erickson Memorial Film Library Instructional Films, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 185)
      - UCONN Instructional Films- Supplement, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 186)
      - University Home Economic Program Includes..., undated (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - Speeches and Writings
      - “Aspects of the Changing Role of Women and Implications for Their Education”, undated (Box 5, Folder 188)
      - “The Challenge of the Modern World to Education”, undated (Box 5, Folder 189)
      - “The Changing Role of Modern Women”- news release, undated (Box 5, Folder 190)
      - “Changing Values in Family Life”- excerpt from address, undated (Box 5, Folder 191)
      - “Changing Values in Family Life”- clippings, notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 192)
      - “Developing Human Resources”, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 193)
      - “Expanding the Services of the Home Economist in Rehabilitation”, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 194)
      - Freshman Interview- “Working Wives”, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 195)
      - “Homemaking Today and Tomorrow”, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 196)
      - Outline for Discussion of Some Social and Economic Problems Related to the Employment of Mother - notecards, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 197)
      - “Professional Opportunities Available in a College of Home Economics”, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 198)
      - “What are the Boundaries of Homemaking”, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 199)
      - “Where is Our Profession Headed”, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - Articles and Speeches
      - Be Proud You're A Housewife!, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 201)
      - Better Kitchen Storage, undated (Box 5, Folder 202)
      - The Big Parade of Women to Work, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 203)
      - The Career Mother, undated (Box 5, Folder 204)
      - The Challenge of Womanpower, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 205)
      - Changing Roles of Men and Women- articles, bibliography, undated (Box 5, Folder 206)
      - Children and Working Mothers, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 207)
      - Conference on the Effective Use of Womanpower, 1955 March 10 - 11 (Box 5, Folder 208)
      - “Continuing Education of Women- Needs, Aspirations, and Plans”, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 209)
      - The Contribution of Home Economics Education to the Position of Women in the World Today, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 210)